Guide to the Karen Landahl Papers 1940-2004
University of Chicago Library
Landahl, Karen. Papers
1940-2004
25 linear feet (50 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Karen Landahl (1951-2003) was a linguist who taught at the University of Chicago, in the Department of Linguistics, from 1982 to 2003. She was also the Academic Director of the Language Labs and Archives and the Language Faculty Resource Center, and the Associate Dean for Computing and Language Technologies at the University. The materials in this collection include teaching materials for the courses she taught, a range of academic papers on various topics in the field of linguistics and speech pathology, and material related to her own research on early language development, craniofacial anomalies, and Japanese phonetics. This collection would be of interest to researchers interested in developments in the field of linguistics and communications disorders between 1980 and 2000.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research, with the exception of material in Series IX, Restricted. This series contains restricted personnel and financial information, grant proposals with social security numbers, evaluative student material, and medical information. Materials in Box 38 are restricted for 50 years from date of record creation. Materials in Box 39 are restricted for 80 years from date of record creation. Materials in Boxes 40-50 are restricted indefinitely.
Biographical Note
Karen Landahl was born on December 20, 1951, to John and Betty Landahl of Tinley Park, Illinois. Her family moved to Flossmoor in 1960, where she attended Homewood-Flossmoor High School. Upon graduation she studied at St. Olaf College, spending her junior year in Oxford. She earned her B.A. in Linguistics in 1974. In 1976 she received an M.A. and in 1982 a Ph.D. from Brown University, both in Linguistics. Her dissertation was entitled "The Onset of Structured Discourse: A Developmental Study of the Acquisition of Language." She examined how five children learned to speak through interactions with parents and caretakers and presented a major challenge to the dominant theories of Noam Chomsky and Steven Pinker. According to her dissertation advisor, Philip Lieberman, Professor of Linguistics at Brown University, she was one of the first people to show that children have different styles of acquiring language.
While working on her dissertation she pursued a second major area of interest as a consultant and a collaborative researcher in Chicago at the Center for Craniofacial Anomalies at the University of Illinois Medical Center. Her work here focused on the effects of Crouzon and Apert syndromes on speech production.
Following a National Science Foundation Postdoctoral Fellowship in Speech Communications at MIT in 1981-2, she returned to Illinois and took a position as an assistant professor at the University of Chicago.
At the University of Chicago she worked on the connections between phonetics, computers, and language learning. In the 1990s, with her student Yukari Hirata, she researched the use of the Visipitch software program in language learning. With this program, students could watch how pitch rises and falls when a native speaks a language, and then learn to imitate it. Landahl had a wide variety of other linguistic interests, including the study of linguistic "others" such as feral children, sign-language using chimps and humans without tongues or with cleft palates, and the origins of human language.
She was diagnosed with cancer in 2000 and her illness rendered her unable to speak. As a result, she moved from classroom teaching to spearhead a program in educational technology as Associate Dean for Computing and Language Technologies. Here she used her knowledge of speech perception and production to become a leader in the use of computers in language teaching.
She died on February 2, 2003.
Scope Note
The collection is organized into nine series, and span the period 1940-2004. The bulk of the collection dates from 1970 to 1990.
Series I, Personal, contains a partial copy of Landahl's curriculum vitae and cartoon clippings.
Series II, Correspondence, contains a small collection of personal and professional correspondence. Materials are arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
Series III, Research, contains materials related to Landahl's research activities. This series is organized into five subseries:
Subseries I, Child Language Development, contains materials related to early language development and Landahl's doctoral dissertation project. This subseries contains transcripts of speech samples, as well as statistical analysis.
Subseries II, Craniofacial Anomalies, contains materials connected to Landahl's work at the Center for Craniofacial Anomalies at the University of Illinois Medical Center.
Subseries III, Japan Visipitch Research Project, contains materials relating to Landahl's study of the use of computers to teach Japanese phonemes and intonation. The bulk of this subseries is made up of tabulated data from research subjects.
Subseries IV, General, contains unlabeled and miscellaneous research materials and notes, as well as materials from several smaller projects on glossectomy, teaching Norwegian, and aprodosia.
Subseries V, Index Cards, contains several card files of index cards. These contain notes on dialectical variations, a phonology and phonetics glossary, as well as cue cards from research projects.
Series IV, Writing, contains photocopies and reprints of articles and chapters authored or co-authored by Landahl. Materials are arranged chronologically.
Series V, Writings by Others, contains photocopies and reprints of a range of academic papers on various topics in the field of linguistics and speech pathology. These include early language development, glossectomy, acoustic perception, and foreign language learning. Materials are arranged alphabetically by author.
Series VI, Professional Activities, contains materials related to Landahl's participation in workshops and conferences. Materials are arranged chronologically.
Series VII, Teaching, contains materials connected to Landahl's teaching career at the University of Chicago. The series contains syllabi, copies of reading materials, lab assignments and instructions, and ungraded student work. Materials are arranged chronologically, with general files of photocopied readings gathered at the end of the series.
Series VIII, Oversize, contains two folders of enlarged research data.
Series IX, Restricted, contains restricted personnel and financial information, grant proposals with social security numbers, evaluative student material, and medical information. Materials in Box 38 are restricted for 50 years from date of record creation. Materials in Box 39 are restricted for 80 years from date of record creation. Materials in Boxes 40-50 are restricted indefinitely.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Language Laboratories and Archives. Records.
McQuown, Norman A., Papers
Subject Headings
Landahl, Karen Louise, 1951-; University of Chicago. Department of Linguistics; Apert's syndrome; Crouzon's disease; Craniofacial dysostosis; Language acquisition; Language acquisition--Computer-assisted learning; Language acquisition--Testing; Linguistics
INVENTORY
- Series I: Personal
  - Curriculum Vitae (Partial), October, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cartoon Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - ASHA Convention, June-August, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Farley, Anne, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General (Professional), 1978-2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hemphill, Rachel, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lieberman, Philip, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NATO Advanced Study Institute, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Peterson-Falzone, Sally, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Speech Research Workshop, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Public Computing, University of Chicago, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series III: Research
  - Subseries I: Early Child Language Development
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Statistical Information and Analysis Notes, circa 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Anna", 52-103 weeks, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Damien", 52-103 weeks, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Duff", 53-104 weeks, 1979-1980 [1/3] (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University – Transcripts – "Duff", 1979-1980 [2/3] (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University – Transcripts – "Duff", 1979-1980 [3/3] (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Kate", 53-104 weeks, 1978-1979 [1/2] (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Kate", 53-104 weeks, 1978-1979 [1/2] (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Megan", 53-104 weeks, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Julia", 53-104 weeks, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - PhD Dissertation, Brown University – Phonemic Inventories, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II: Craniofacial Anomalies
    - Apert study report - Draft fragments, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Apert Crouzon – Proposal with Modifications, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Apert Crouzon – Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Apert Crouzon, Vocal Tract Modelling, Notebook, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Tammy" – Spectograms, March, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Rachel" – Spectograms, March, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Joe" – Spectograms, March, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Ken" – Spectograms, March, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Spectograms (Alba Type), undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Spectograms with Flashcards, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Spectograms and Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Session Transcript with Utterance and Phoneme List, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Flashcards – Stops and Liquids, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "The Template" – undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Research Protocol Guide, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Subseries III: Japanese Language Learning
    - Japanese Teaching Manuals, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Miscellaneous, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Spectograms, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Records, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Japan Visipitch Study - Bibliography, circa 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #112, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #113, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #114, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #115, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #122, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #123, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #124, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #125, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #131, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #132, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #133, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #134, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #135, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #211, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #212, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #213, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #214, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #215, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #222, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #223, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #224, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #225, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #226, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #227, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #231, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #232, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #233, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #234, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #235, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Project Mayumi - Experiment Sound Files, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Subseries IV: General
    - Midwest Clinical Phonology Meeting, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1987 [1/2] (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Midwest Clinical Phonology Meeting, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1987 [2/2] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Glossectomy Project – Landahl and Karnell, 1987 [1/4] (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Glossectomy Project – Landahl and Karnell, 1987 [2/4] (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Glossectomy Project – Landahl and Karnell, 1973-1992 [3/4] (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Glossectomy Project – Landahl and Karnell, 1973-1992 [4/4] (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - MacNorsk Project – Notes on Norwegian, undated [1/3] (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - MacNorsk Project – Notes on Norwegian, 1996-1997 [2/3] (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - MacNorsk Project – Notes on Norwegian, 1996-1997 [3/3] (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - MacNorsk Project, Interactive Norwegian, ScandiLingFest, 1992-1995 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - General – Acoustics Data [1/2] (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - General – Acoustics Data [2/2] (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - General - Scatter Plots, A, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - General - Scatter Plots, F, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - General - Scatter Plots, G, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - General - Scatter Plots, I, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - General - Scatter Plots, J, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - General - Scatter Plots, K, undated [1/3] (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - General - Scatter Plots, K, undated [2/3] (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - General - Scatter Plots, K, undated [3/3] (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - General - Scatter Plots, L, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - General – Research data and Cluster Graphs, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - General – Cluster Graphs, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - General - Original Pitch Contours, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - General – Scatter Plots and Tables, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - General – Data and graphs, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - General – Data and graphs, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - General – Data Tables, undated [1/2] (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - General – Data Tables, undated [2/2] (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - General – Research Papers, 1992-1998 [1/2] (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - General – Individual-based pronunciation training in Japanese - IRB, proposals, and reports, 1997-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - General - Aprosodia Tape Transcript, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - General – CHAT Transcript System Notes, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - General - Misperception Analysis, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - General - Fundamental Problems in Phonetics Notebooks, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - General - Linguistics Experiment, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - General - Perception of stops in the environment of liquids - Blank consent forms, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - General - Perception of stops in the environment of liquids - Results, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Subseries V: Index Cards
    - Index Cards – Conversation Analysis, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Word Flashcards - /b/ and /p/, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Word Flashcards - /b/ and /p/, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Index Cards and slides - Graphs, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Index Card File - Masters, A-G, undated (Box 15)
    - Index Card File - Masters, H-P, undated (Box 16)
    - Index Card File - Masters, Q-Z, undated (Box 17)
    - Index Card File - Glossarial Handbook, Hamp and Landahl, undated (Box 18)
    - Index Card File - Scripts and Books, undated (Box 19)
    - Index Card File - Catalog Codes, Lab, Computer Tapes, and Music, undated (Box 20)
    - Index Card File - Languages and Dialects, undated [1/2] (Box 21)
    - Index Card File - Languages and Dialects, undated [2/2] (Box 22)
    - Index Card File – Articles and Tape, undated (Box 23)
    - Includes audiocassette tape, "Imitations." (Box 23)
- Series IV: Writing
  - Effect of Aberrant Supralaryngeal Vocal Tracts on Transfer Function – Landahl and Peterson-Falzone – Speech and Language: Advances in Basics Research and Practice, circa 1975 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - On the Role of Invariant Acoustic Properties and Context Dependent Cues – Landahl and Blumstein – Brown University, circa 1975 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Identification by adults of vowel sounds produced by an infant – Landahl and Mikos – Brown University Working Papers in Linguistics, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Formant Frequency Patterns in Anomalous Supralaryngeal Vocal Tracts – Landahl and Robinson – Brown University Working Papers in Linguistics, Vol III, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Cues for Interpreting Early Child Speech – Speech Communication Papers, Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Abnormal Laryngeal Vocal Quality in Ectodermal Dysplasia – Archives of Otolaryngology, May, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Review: Speech and Language, Norman J. Lass – Contemporary Psychology, Vol 27.6, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Congenital Malformation of the Speech Tract in Humans and its Developmental Consequences – Landahl and Gould, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - The /b/-/w/ Contrast and Considerations of Syllable Duration – Landahl and Maxwell - Papers from the Nineteenth Regional Meeting, Chicago Linguistics Society, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Imitation in Phonological Acquisition – Landahl, Rasco, Gould, and Mishra - University of Chicago Working Papers in Linguistics, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Abstracts, Miscellaneous, circa 1985 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Phoneticxs Entries – Encyclopedia Britannica Micropaedia, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Development of the Vowel Space in Children with Apert Syndrome – Landahl and Hasner, circa 1987 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Fundamental Frequency Anchors and Bands – Landahl and Lierberman, circa 1989 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Acoustic Invariance in Glossectomee Speech - Landahl and Karnell, January 31, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Comparison of Fundamental Frequency and Perturbation Measurements – Landahl, Karnell, and Hall - Journal of Voice 9.4, December, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Craniofacial Anomalies and the Evolution of Human Speech – Typescript with edits, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Effects of Congenital Malformations on Speech Development – Landahl and Peterson-Falzone, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Fourier and Linear Predictive Analyses of Aberrant Vowel Formants – Landahl and Peterson-Falzone - Proceedings of the 18th Congress of the International Association of Logopedics and Phoniatrics, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Imitation in Early Language Development – Presentation, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Otisis Media, Sensory Deprivation, and Speech Sound Perception – Proposal – Landahl and Gould, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Questioning the Continuum: The Use of V[r/l][d/g] Evidence in Gestural Theories of Speech Perception – Landahl, Hemphill, Hirata, Lowenstein, and Dainora, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - The Stop-Glide Contrast and Considerations of Phonetic Context – Landahl and Maxwell - MIT Speech Communications Working Papers, Vol III, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - "Syndromes" of Linguistic Development – Landahl, Farley, and Ziolkowski, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks and miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Series V: Writing by Others
  - Anderson, S., and R. Port – Evidence for Syllable Structure, Stress, and Juncture from Segmental Durations – Journal of Phonetics, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Bates, E., and B. Macwhinney - Competition, Variance and Language Learning, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Bever, T. – Normal Acquisition Processes Explain the Critical Period for Language Learning, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Bever, T. – Psychologically Real Grammar Emerges Because of Its Role in Language Acquisition, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Billings, S., and K. Gruber - Systematicity and Speaker Variation in Acoustic Realization, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Bless, H., and Faber – Videostroboscopic Evaluation of the Larynx - Ear, Nose and Throat Journal, undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Blumstein, S. – Acoustic Invariance in Speech Production – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, October 1979 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Blumstein, S., and K.N. Stevens – Phonetic Features and Acoustic Invariance - Cognition, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Boysson-Bardies and Vihman – Adaptation to Language: Evidence from Babbling and First Words in Four Languages, 1991; and Boysson-Bardies, Sagart, and Durand - Discernible Differences in the Babbling of Infants According to Target Language, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Brentari – American Sign Language Phonology – undated (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Broad, D.J. – Toward Defining Acoustic Phonetic Equivalence - Phonetica, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Browman, C.P., and L. Goldstein – Articulatory Phonology, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Brown, W.S., T. Murry, and D. Hughes – Comfortable Effort Level: An Experimental Variable – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, September 1976 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Bull, D., R. Eilers, and D. Oller – Infants Discrimination of Intensity Variation into Multisyllabic Stimuli - Journal of the Acoustic Society of America, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Carden, G., and A. Levitt – Evidence for Phonetic Processing of Cues to Place of Articulation: Perceived Manner Affects Perceived Place - Perception and Psychophysics, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Cohn, A. – Quantitative Characterization of Degree of Coarticulation in CV Tokens, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Cole, R. – Listening for Mispronunciations: A measure of what we hear during speech – Perception and Psychophysics, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Copper and Eady - Metrical Phonology in Speech Production - Journal of Memory and Language, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Darden, B.J. – A Critical Look at Natural Phonology, and Explanation and Reality in Phonology, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Delattre, P. – Some Factors of Vowel Duration and Their Cross-Linguistic Validity, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Denton, J., Y. Hirata, and S. Sogslanova – Reassessment: Liquid Stop Sequences, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Dommelan, W. – Acoustic parameters in Human Speaker Recognition - Language and Speech, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Duanmu, S. – Syllabic Weight and Syllabic Duration – Phonology, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Eimas, P., E. Jusczyk, and J. Vigorito – Speech Perception in Infants – Science, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Eimas, P. and J. Miller – Studies on the Categorization of Speech by Infants – Cognition, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Elfenbein, Waziri, and Morris - Verbal Communication Skills of Six Children with Craniofacial Anomalies - Cleft Palate Journal - Photocopy, offprint, notes, and clipping, 1981-1988 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Emanuel, F.W., and D.T Counihan – Some Characteristics of Oral and Nasal Air Flow During Plosive Consonant Production, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Erbaugh, M. – Pre-Narrative Roots of Time Reference in Child Mandarin, July 1989 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Farley, A. – Acoustic Cues to Discourse Units: A Study of Paragraph Marking, undated (Box 26, Folder 17)